JOHANN EMMANUEL JESÚS OSNAYA

SUMMARY

Professional with problem-solving thinking with 2+ years of experience in web development. Proficient in identifying improvements and solutions for projects built in different technologies through ingenious innovation. Capable of working in a team and with clients. Ability to self-learn and rapidly adapt to emerging technologies to propose different client solution options.

EXPERIENCE

Arc XP Engineer (Freelance), 02/2024 - Current C Infinity Solutions LLC

- Contributed to the development of RESTful endpoints, facilitated data pipeline ingestion of large files via AWS S3 buckets and lambda functions, and executed effective searches in Open Search database for customized Arc XP Content Sources utilizing Typescript and Nest Is.
- Successfully implemented React-based layouts and components for Arc XP, ensuring adherence to highest coding standards and meeting all client specifications based on UX designs from Figma.
- Achieved successful design, architecture, and implementation of a comprehensive mailing process framework along with a webhook for efficient email tracking using Mailgun.

Backend Developer, 08/2023 - Current Interware de México

- Designed and developed various features for the financial web application ButterBuck, focusing on administration, digitalization, and automation of enterprise finance. Utilized AWS S3, EC2, Node Js, Typescript, Nest Js, MongoDB and Elasticsearch in the architecture design.
- Utilized React, Next Js, and Ant Design to create components that adhere to client requirements for charting and user interaction with financial data.
- Enhanced the user experience by designing, developing, and automating ButterBuck's payment process through Stripe and Nest Js.
- Resolved ButterBuck's requirements by providing a solution that boosted the budget and addressed data challenges. Successfully eliminated technical debt left by previous project administrators, paving the way for advancement in next phase initiatives.



CONTACT

Phone: (+52) 5516449197

Email: johann.osnaya@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Typescript
- Javascript
- Java
- C++
- Python
- C#
- Rect
- Redux
- HTML
- CSS
- Node Js
- Nest Is
- Docker
- MongoDB
- Elasticsearch
- SQL Server
- Spring Framework
- Jest
- Redux
- AWS

 Increased efficiency of docker terminal for service in Mexico and international shipment by performing maintenance tasks, refactoring business logic, updating dependencies and Hibernate version.
 Utilized Java and SQL Server 2019 with Spring Framework within a WebSphere Application Server V 9.0 environment.

Cloud Administrator, 06/2023 - 08/2023 Biplus Data

- Managed instances, user creation, and Linux virtual machines while overseeing asset provisioning. Configured load balancers and ensured optimal connection health for VPCs at Televisa using Oracle Cloud Infrastructure.
- Assistance in resolution of critical failures of providers in war rooms and as translator in technical discussion in SR video calls with Oracle.

Jr Innovation Strategist (Internship), 03/2018 - 08/2018 Interware de México

- Enabled clients to gain actionable insights about their brand by building and implementing a Chatbot platform connected to various SNS platforms like Messenger and Facebook using technologies such as Node Js, Microsoft LUIS, and React with a Microservices Architecture.
- Achieved a low-cost solution and enhanced conversational data analysis by testing multiple technologies for the implementation of the Chatbots platform.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering, Communication and Electronics Engineering, 2022

Instituto Politécnico Nacional - Escuela Superior de Ingeniería Mecánica y E.

Technician - Degree., Digital Graphics Designer, 2017
Instituto Politécnico Nacional - CECyT #2 Miguel Bernard

LANGUAGES Spanish: First Language English: C1 Japanese: B1 Advanced Intermediate

CERTIFICATIONS

- Fullstack Web Development
- Frontend Web Development (Oracle ONE)
- Javascript Data Structures and Algorithms
- Typescript Certification